A Guide to the Licenses of the Virginia Auditor of Public Accounts, 1879-1927
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Licenses of the Virginia Auditor of Public Accounts, 1879-1927
The Library of Virginia
262 volumes.
Auditor of Public Accounts.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
No acquisition information available. Received circa 1930.
Biographical/Historical Information
These records are part of the Auditor of Public Accounts, Administration of State Government: Revenue Assesment and Collection - Fees and Licenses.
Virginia's general assembly passed an act to assign the duties of the board of fiscal auditors and the solicitor general in 1792, assigning them to a single auditor of public accounts. All receipts and disbursements were made only upon their warrant to the treasurer, and the auditor's books were the standard against which those of the treasurer were checked.
Following the Civil War, inadequate bookkeeping procedures and embezzlements of state funds resulted in a public demand for corrective action. The state government reorganization act passed by General Assembly in 1927 led to the abolishment of both the auditor of public accounts and a second auditor. These offices were replaced by the office of the comptroller to monitor the receipt and disbursment of state funds, and a new office of auditor of public accounts, anserable to the general assembly, to examine the books of state and local government agencies.
Scope and Content
Volumes contain names and addresses of licensees, types of licenses issued, nature of business, beginning and expiration dates of licenses, and fees charged. Volumes prior to 1918 are titled "Licenses other than Liquor."
Arrangement
The volumes are arranged chronologically by year and alphabetically by locality therein.
Contents List
- Licenses of the Virginia Auditor of Public Accounts, 1879-1927.
  - A-K, May, 1879
  - K-Y, May, 1879
  - A-J, Nov, 1879
  - Mecklenburg-York, 1879
  - 1879-1880
  - A-H May, 1880
  - Counties, H-Y May, 1880
  - Nov, 1880
  - Counties, M-T Nov, 1880
  - 1880-1881
  - May, 1881
  - Nov, 1881
  - Counties, A-K May, 1882
  - Counties, L-Y May, 1882
  - Nov, 1882
  - Cities 1883
  - May, 1883
  - Nov, 1883
  - 1884
  - May, 1884
  - May, 1885
  - Nov, 1885
  - Nov, 1885 - May, 1886
  - May, 1887
  - July, 1887
  - May-Nov, 1887
  - Counties July, 1887
  - Nov, 1887-May, 1888
  - May-Nov, 1888
  - Nov, 1888-May, 1889
  - Nov, 1889
  - Nov, 1889-May, 1890
  - Cities, 1890
  - May - Nov, 1890
  - Nov, 1890- May, 1891
  - 1890-1893
  - Counties, May, 1891
  - Counties, Nov, 1891
  - Cities, Nov, 1891
  - Cities, 1892
  - Counties, 1892
  - Cities, May, 1892
  - Counties, 1893
  - Counties, Nov, 1893
  - Counties, 1893-1894
  - Cities, May, 1894
  - Cities, Nov, 1894
  - Counties, Nov, 1894
  - Cities, Nov, 1894-May, 1895
  - Counties, Nov, 1894-May, 1895
  - Cities, May-Nov, 1895
  - Counties, May-July, 1895
  - Counties, July-Nov, 1895
  - Cities, May, 1896
  - Counties, May, 1896
  - Cities, July, 1896
  - Counties, July, 1896
  - Cities, Dec, 1896
  - Counties, Dec, 1896
  - Cities, July, 1897
  - Counties, July, 1897
  - Cities, Dec, 1897
  - Cities, July, 1898
  - Counties, July, 1898
  - Cities, Dec, 1898
  - Counties, Dec, 1898
  - Cities, July, 1899
  - Counties, July, 1899
  - Counties, Dec, 1899
  - Cities, Jan, 1900
  - Counties, Jan, 1900
  - Cities, July, 1900
  - Counties, July, 1900
  - Accomack-Cumberland (Counties), July, 1900-Jan 1901
  - Lancaster-Prince George (Counties), July, 1900-Jan 1901
  - Counties, July, 1901
  - Alexandria-Winchester (Cities), Jan, 1902
  - Accomack-Lunenburg (Counties), Jan, 1902
  - Madison-York (Counties), Jan, 1902
  - Accomack-Nottoway (Counties), July, 1902-Jan, 1903
  - Alexandria-Williamsburg (Cities), Jan-July, 1903
  - Accomack-Lunenburg (Counties), Jan-July, 1903
  - Alexandria-Winchester (Cities), July, 1903
  - Madison-York (Counties), July, 1903
  - Accomac(k)-Winchester (Cities), Jan, 1904
  - Alexandria-Winchester (Cities), Jan, 1904
  - Jan, 1905
  - A-H, Jan-July, 1905
  - G-N, Jan-July, 1905
  - O-W, Jan-July, 1905
  - A-W, July-Dec, 1905
  - Jan-July, 1906
  - Cities July, 1906-Jan, 1907
  - A-L July, 1906-Jan, 1907
  - M-Y July, 1906-Jan, 1907
  - Jan, 1907
  - Jan, 1908
  - Accomack-Smyth Jan, 1908
  - Accomac-Winchester Jan, 1909
  - Accomac-Winchester July, 1909
  - Cities July, 1910
  - Accomack-Lunenburg July, 1910
  - Madison-York July, 1910
  - Accomac(k)-Winchester Dec, 1910
  - Cities July, 1911
  - Accomac(k)-Winchester July, 1911
  - Accomack-Orange (Counties) 1912
  - Accomack-Dinwiddie(Counties) 1912
  - Elizabeth City-Rappahannock (Cities) 1912
  - Richmond-York (Cities) 1912
  - Accomack-Winchester July, 1912
  - Alexandria-Winchester July, 1912
  - Page-York July, 1912
  - Dec, 1912
  - Accomack-York Dec, 1912
  - Alexandria-Winchester July, 1913
  - Accomack-Lunenburg (Counties) July, 1913
  - Madison-York July, 1913
  - Accomack-Winchester Dec, 1913
  - Accomack-York 1913-1915
  - Alexandria-Winchester 1913-1915
  - Alexandria-Winchester July, 1914
  - Accomack-Lunenburg July, 1914
  - Madison-York July, 1914
  - Accomack-Winchester Dec, 1914
  - Alexandria-Winchester 1915
  - Accomack-York 1915
  - Accomack-Dickenson July, 1915
  - Madison-Rockbridge July, 1915
  - Alexandria-Winchester (Cities) July, 1915
  - Dinwiddie-Lunenburg(Counties) July, 1915
  - Rockingham-York (Counties) July, 1915
  - Accomack-Lunenburg Dec, 1915
  - Cities Dec, 1915
  - Madison-York Dec, 1915
  - Alexandria-Winchester (Cities) July, 1916
  - Accomack-Cumberland (Counties) July, 1916 (Volume 1)
  - Dickenson-King and Queen (Counties) July, 1916 (Volume 2)
  - King William-Nottoway (Counties) July, 1916 (Volume 3)
  - Orange-Rockingham (Counties) July, 1916 (Volume 4)
  - Russell-York (Counties) July, 1916 (Volume 5)
  - Accomack-Frederick (Counties) Dec, 1916 (Volume 1)
  - Giles-Nottoway (Counties) Dec, 1916 (Volume 2)
  - Orange-York (Counties) Dec, 1916 (Volume 3)
  - Alexandria-Winchester (Cities) Dec, 1916
  - Accomack-Cumberland (Counties) July, 1917 (Volume 1)
  - Dickenson-King and Queen (Counties) July, 1917 (Volume 2)
  - King William-Nottoway (Counties) July, 1917 (Volume 3)
  - Orange-Rockingham (Counties) July, 1917 (Volume 4)
  - Russell-York (Counties) July, 1917 (Volume 5)
  - Alexandria-Winchester July, 1917 (Volume 6)
  - Accomack-Frederick July, 1917-Jan, 1918 (Volume 1)
  - Giles-Pulaski July, 1917-Jan, 1918 (Volume 2)
  - Rappahannock-York (Cities) July, 1917-Jan, 1918 (Volume 3)
  - Accomack-Cumberland July, 1918 (Volume 1)
  - Dickenson-King and Queen July, 1918 (Volume 2)
  - King William-Nottoway July, 1918 (Volume 3)
  - Orange-Rockingham July, 1918 (Volume 4)
  - Russell-York July, 1918 (Volume 5)
  - Alexandria-Winchester July, 1918 (Volume 6)
  - Accomack-Frederick Dec, 1918 (Volume 1)
  - Giles-Pulaski Dec, 1918 (Volume 2)
  - Rappahannock-York Dec, 1918 (Volume 3)
  - Alexandria-Winchester Dec, 1918 (Volume 4)
  - Accomack-Cumberland July, 1919 (Volume 1)
  - Giles-Pulaski July, 1919 (Volume 2)
  - King William-Nottoway July, 1919 (Volume 3)
  - Orange-Rockingham July, 1919 (Volume 4)
  - Russell-York July, 1919 (Volume 5)
  - Accomack-Frederick Dec, 1919 (Volume 1)
  - Giles-Pulaski Dec, 1919 (Volume 2)
  - Rappahannock-York Dec, 1919 (Volume 3)
  - Alexandria-Winchester Dec, 1919 (Volume 4)
  - Accomack-Cumberland July, 1920 (Volume 1)
  - Dickenson-King and Queen July, 1920 (Volume 2)
  - King William-Nottoway July, 1920 (Volume 3)
  - Orange-Rockingham July, 1920 (Volume 4)
  - Russell-York July, 1920 (Volume 5)
  - Alexandria-Winchester July, 1920 (Volume 6)
  - Accomack-Frederick Dec, 1920 (Volume 1)
  - Giles-Pulaski Dec, 1920 (Volume 2)
  - Rappahannock-York Dec, 1920 (Volume 3)
  - Alexandria-Winchester Dec, 1920 (Volume 4)
  - Accomack-Cumberland July, 1921 (Volume 1)
  - Dickenson-King William July, 1921 (Volume 2)
  - Lancaster-Nottoway July, 1921 (Volume 3)
  - Orange-Rockingham July, 1921 (Volume 4)
  - Russell-York July, 1921 (Volume 5)
  - Alexandria-Winchester July, 1921 (Volume 6)
  - Accomack-Frederick Dec, 1921 (Volume 1)
  - Giles-Pulaski Dec, 1921 (Volume 2)
  - Rappahannock-York Dec, 1921 (Volume 3)
  - Alexandria-Winchester Dec, 1921 (Volume 4)
  - Accomack-Cumberland July, 1922 (Volume 1)
  - Dickenson-King William July, 1922 (Volume 2)
  - Lancaster-Nottoway July, 1922 (Volume 3)
  - Orange-Rockingham July, 1922 (Volume 4)
  - Russell-York July, 1922 (Volume 5)
  - Alexandria-Winchester July, 1922 (Volume 6)
  - Accomack-Frederick Dec, 1922 (Volume 1)
  - Giles-Pulaski Dec, 1922 (Volume 2)
  - Rappahannock-York Dec, 1922 (Volume 3)
  - Alexandria-Winchester Dec, 1922 (Volume 4)
  - Accomack-Frederick July, 1923 (Volume 1)
  - Giles-Pulaski July, 1923 (Volume 2)
  - Rappahannock-York July, 1923 (Volume 3)
  - Alexandria-Winchester July, 1923 (Volume 4)
  - Accomack-Frederick Dec, 1923 (Volume 1)
  - Giles-Pulaski Dec, 1923 (Volume 2)
  - Rappahanock-York Dec, 1923 (Volume 3)
  - Alexandria-Winchester Dec, 1923 (Volume 4)
  - Accomack-Frederick July, 1924 (Volume 1)
  - Giles-Pulaski July, 1924 (Volume 2)
  - Rappahannock-York July, 1924 (Volume 3)
  - Alexandria-Winchester July, 1924 (Volume 4)
  - Accomack-Frederick Dec, 1924 (Volume 1)
  - Giles-Montgomery Dec, 1924 (Volume 2)
  - Nansemond-York Dec, 1924 (Volume 3)
  - Alexandria-Winchester Dec, 1924 (Volume 4)
  - Accomack-Frederick July, 1925 (Volume 1)
  - Giles-Pulaski July, 1925 (Volume 2)
  - Rappahannock-York July, 1925 (Volume 3)
  - Alexandria-Winchester July, 1925 (Volume 4)
  - Accomack-Frederick July, 1925 (Volume 1)
  - Giles-Montgomery Dec, 1925 (Volume 2)
  - Nansemond-York Dec, 1925 (Volume 3)
  - Alexandria-Winchester Dec, 1925 (Volume 4)
  - Accomack-Frederick July, 1926 (Volume 1)
  - Giles-Pulaski July, 1926 (Volume 2)
  - Rappahannock-York July, 1926 (Volume 3)
  - Alexandria-Winchester July, 1926 (Volume 4)
  - Accomack-Frederick Dec, 1926 (Volume 1)
  - Giles-Pulaski Dec, 1926 (Volume 2)
  - Rappahannock-York Dec, 1926 (Volume 3)
  - Alexandria-Winchester Dec, 1926 (Volume 4)
  - Accomack-Frederick July, 1927 (Volume 1)
  - Giles-Pulaski July, 1927 (Volume 2)
  - Rappahannock-York July, 1927 (Volume 3)
  - Alexandria-Winchester July, 1927 (Volume 4)
  - Accomack-Frederick Dec, 1927 (Volume 1)
  - Giles-Pulaski Dec, 1927 (Volume 2)
  - Rappahannock-York Dec, 1927 (Volume 3)
  - Alexandria-Winchester Dec, 1927 (Volume 4)